Guide to the Scrolls of Fire Screen Prints, 1979 RL.11024
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Scrolls of Fire screen prints
1979
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jewish Heritage Foundation of North Carolina
Reisinger, Dan
RL.11024
2 Linear Feet 18 screen prints (70 cm x 50 cm)
The Scrolls of Fire screen prints is a partial collection of the images created by Israeli painter and graphic artist Dan Reisinger (1934- ) to illustrate verses by Israeli poet Abba Kovner. Reisinger's illustrations and Kovner's verses were published with parallel Hebrew and English text in 1981 as Megilot ha-esh [Scrolls of Fire: a nation fighting for its life: fifty-two chapters of Jewish martyrology].
Biographical Note
Dan Reisinger (1934- ) is an Israeli painter and graphic artist known for his posters and corporate logo design for El Al Israeli Airlines and other organizations.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Collection Overview
The Scrolls of Fire screen prints are a partial collection of the 53 prints relating to the poetry of Abba Kovner that Dan Reisinger created in 1979. Kovner's verses and Reisinger's illustrations were published with parallel Hebrew and English text in 1981 as Megilot ha-esh [Scrolls of Fire: a nation fighting for its life: fifty-two chapters of Jewish martyrology]. According to the artist's website, the screen prints "depict the spiritual and physical fight for survival of the Jewish people throughout history." The prints in this collection are from a limited edition of 180 printings.
Related Material
Jewish Heritage Foundation of North Carolina records, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Arrangement
The prints are arranged numerically according to the numbering of their corresponding Megilot ha-esh [Scrolls of Fire] verses. The chapter titles from the English translations of Kovner's verses follow the chapter numbers in the folder listing.
Jewish artists; Artists -- Israel; Screen prints -- Israel; Jews -- Persecutions -- Illustrated works; Kovner, Abba, 1918-1987 -- Megilot ha-esh -- Illustrated works; Jewish Heritage Foundation of North Carolina; Reisinger, Dan
- Scrolls of Fire screen prints, 1979; 1
  - 1, "Weeping of a prophet", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Caption from 1981 publication: "Destruction of the First Temple, 586 B.C.E."
    Jews -- Persecutions -- Illustrated works; Screen prints -- Israel; Artists -- Israel; Kovner, Abba, 1918-1987 -- Megilot ha-esh -- Illustrated works; Jewish Heritage Foundation of North Carolina; Reisinger, Dan
  - 4, "A stiff-necked people", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Caption from 1981 publication: "A Statue in the Temple; The Decree of Caligula, 40 C. E."
  - 5, "This night", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Caption from 1981 publication: "The Destruction of the Second Temple, 70"
  - 6, "The Rock and the people", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Caption from 1981 publication: "The Fall of Masada, 73"
  - 7, "Their blood ran down to the sea", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Caption from 1981 publication: "The Diaspora Rebellion, 115-117"
  - 9, "Transgress and suffer not death", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Caption from 1981 publication: "The Moment of Conversion, 135"
  - 10, "The ten martyrs", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Caption from 1981 publication: "The Ten Martyrs (1), 135-138"
  - 11, "And the ones I go on remembering", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Caption from 1981 publication: "The Ten Martyrs (2), 135-138"
  - 13, "A fire consumed your home", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Caption from 1981 publication: "The Destruction of Jewish Communities in Southern Arabia, 624"
  - 17, "Mina, Gitele, Zipporah", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Caption from 1981 publication: "Persecutions in Germany, 1180"
  - 18, "Oh your brother's blood cries from the Maghreb", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Caption from 1981 publication: "Decrees of Conversion in Islamic Lands, 1146"
  - 25, "The Vale of Tears ", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Caption from 1981 publication: "Years of the Black Plague, 1348-1352"
  - 32, "To the ends of the earth: a page from the notebook of the Marranos", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Caption from 1981 publication: "The Burning of the Marranos, 16th and 17th Centuries"
  - 34, "Of children who were captured", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Caption from 1981 publication: "The Decree of the Cantonists in Russia, 1827-1854"
  - 37, "Storms in the South", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Caption from 1981 publication: "Pogroms in South Russia, 1881-1883"
  - 43, "The chosen people ", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Caption from 1981 publication: "Kovno, 1943"
  - 46, "The ghetto burns", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Caption from 1981 publication: "Warsaw, April 23, 1943"
  - 52, "And let us remember", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Caption from 1981 publication: [no caption]